《星河战队》
全世界的青年男女
Young people from all over the globe...
为全人类的未来奋战
are joining up to fight for the future.
- 我要出力 - 我要出力
- I'm doing my part. - I'm doing my part.
- 我要出力 - 我也要出力
- I'm doing my part. - I'm doing my part too.
他们全在出力 你呢?
They're doing their part, are you?
加入机动部队 拯救世界
Join the Mobile Infantry and save the world.
入伍就能获得公民权
Service guarantees citizenship.
(你想知道更多吗?)
(虫族陨石)
虫族陨石再度侵犯地球
The bugs send another meteor our way...
这次我们有所准备
but this time we're ready.
地球的防卫日益精良
Planetary defences are better than ever.
(你想知道更多吗?)
虫族陨石来自克兰达夫星球
Klendathu, source of the bug meteor attacks...
环绕着双子星系统运行
orbits a twin star system whose brutal gravitational forces...
附近的带状行星群带来
produce an unlimited supply of bug meteorites...
大量的虫族陨石
in the form of this asteroid belt.
为了捍卫太阳系
To ensure the safety of our solar system...
必须消灭克兰达夫星球
Klendathu must be eliminated.
现在从克兰达夫星球现场
We break net now and take you live to Klendathu...
转播这场大战
where the invasion has begun.
卫星连线 2...1...开始
EXQ uplink on two, one. You're on.
- 我们刚降落在... - 快 快 快!
- We'vejust landed here on what cap troopers... - Move, move, move!
- 被称为大K星的战场 - 快! 走! 走!
- are calling Big K, - Come on! Move, move!
- 第六机动部队正展开攻击 - 快!
- with the 6th Mobile Infantry Division! - Come on!
这丑陋的星球全是大虫
It's an ugly planet, a bug planet!
威胁人类的生存
A planet hostile to life as we know it!
救命啊!
Help me!
- 快走 快 快 - 快!
- Come on! Go, go, go! - Keep moving!
快离开这里
Get out of here now!
基顿 不!
Kitten, no!
(一年前)
瑞哥...瑞哥...瑞哥!
Rico. Rico. Rico!
专心点
Pay attention.
对不起 瑞斯加科先生
Sorry, Mr Rasczak.
总而言之
Let's sum up.
今年我们谈过民主制度失败的原因
This year we explored the failure of democracy...
- 坏家伙 - 社会学家...
- Bad boy. - how the social scientists brought our world...
让世界陷入混乱
to the brink of chaos.
我们谈到退伍军人终于接管统治...
We talked about the veterans, how they took control...
长久以来使得地球得以安定
and imposed the stability that has lasted for generations since.
这些是事实让你们学到了什么?
You know these facts...
我问你为何只有公民才能投票?
but have I taught you anything of value this year?
你 为什么只有公民才有投票权?
You. Why are only citizens allowed to vote?
这是一种奖赏
It's a reward,
那是为联邦政府服务得到的奖励
what the Federation gives you for doing Federal Service.
不对 不对
No. No.
赐与的权利没有价值
Something given has no value.
投票权是政治权
Look, when you vote, you are exercising political authority.
那就是力量 力量就是暴力
You're using force. And force, my friends, is violence,
暴力是所有权力的来源
the supreme authority from which all other authority is derived.
我妈妈说暴力解决不了问题
Uh, my mother always said violence never solves anything.
真的?
Really?
我真好奇广岛之父会不会这么说
I wonder what the city fathers of Hiroshima would say about that.
你
You.
大概不会这么说 因为广岛被炸了
They probably wouldn't say anything. Hiroshima was destroyed.
没错
Correct.
历史证明赤裸裸的...
Naked force has resolved more issues...
暴力解决许多问题
throughout history than any other factor.
暴力解决不了问题的论调...
The contrary opinion, that violence never solves anything,
...只是自欺欺人的想法
is wishful thinking at its worst.
忘记历史教训的人将付出代价
People who forget that always pay.
瑞哥 在道德上...
Rico, what's the moral difference, if any...
公民和平民有何不同?
between a civilian and a citizen?
公民接受政府赋与的责任...
A citizen accepts personal responsibility for the safety...
并且誓死捍卫地球
of the body politic, defending it with his life.
- 平民则不然 - 标准答案
- A civilian does not. - The exact words of the text.
可是你了解吗? 你相信吗?
But do you understand it? Do you believe it?
- 不知道 - 那是当然的
- I don't know. - Of course you don't.
就算是死到临头
I doubt anyone here would recognize civic virtue...
你们都不了解公民的责任 第三节下课 第四节五分钟后上课
if it reached up and bit you in the ass.
别在这里
Not here.
来吧 咱们去看数学课的成绩
Come on, let's see if they posted the math final.
- 瑞哥 赢得了泰斯拉队吗? - 我们会痛宰他们
- Rico, we gonna take Tesla? - We're gonna kill 'em.
记住 毕业生都得填写710表格
Remember, all graduating seniors must fill out a 710 form.
星舰军校最重视数学成绩
First thing Fleet Academy looks at is your math scores.
祝我好运
Wish me luck.
(艾邦妮兹 数学97%)
- 要走了 - 干得好
- Way to go. - Good job.
该你了 等一下
Your turn. Hold on.
我去找马可 他姐姐在星际舰队
I want to talk to Marco. His sister's at Fleet.
- 马可 - 嗨 卡门
- Marco. - Hi, Carmen.
- 你姐有消息吗? - 她当上飞行员
- What do you hear about Roxy? - She made pilot.
(瑞哥 数学35%)
35% 真棒
Thirty-five percent. Very nice.
大伙看 35%
Look at that. Thirty-five percent, ladies and gentlemen.
分数真高
Big numbers.
- 卡尔 - 抱歉
- Carl. - Sorry.
你们还没上床吧 别骗我
So, you haven't done it yet, have you? Don't lie.
我并不急
I'm not in any hurry.
- 有人在等你 - 那么?
- Others are waiting. - And?
- 你能猜到她在想什么? - 不必猜
- Did you read her mind? - Don't have to.
她在想什么很明显
It's pretty clear what she wants.
是呀 我要的是卡门
Yeah, but I want Carmen.
- 你想得要死 - 再见 马可
- Aw, you got it bad. - Bye, Marco.
别忘了下午的事
Hey, don't forget about this afternoon.
他老是为了亲你芳泽耽误正事
He's always late when he walks you home to fish for a kiss.
快走开
Get out of here.
- 马可的姐姐当上飞行员 - 你也会的
- Marco's sister made pilot. - So will you.
想想看 如果要驾驶五十万吨重的星际战舰
I mean, imagine flying a half a million tons of starship.
你就得勇气十足
You gotta have nerves of steel.
当然 你有没有种呢?
Yeah, you do. Let's see how yours hold up.
开始吧
You may begin.
这只是一只虫 戴上护镜
Aw, come on, it's just a bug. You better put your goggles on.
只是一只虫?
"Just a bug."
人类自以为是大自然主宰者
We humans like to think we are nature's finest achievement.
其实并不然
I'm afraid it just isn't true.
这只甲虫远比人类优良
This Arkellian sand beetle is superior in many ways.
它的繁殖力很强 没有私心...
It reproduces in vast numbers, has no ego...
不会恐惧 绝不怕死
has no fear, doesn't now about death...
它是虫族社会完美的一份子
and so is the perfect selfless member of society.
人类创造了艺术数学...
But humans have created art, mathematics...
和星际旅行
and interstellar travel.
没错 不过千万别自大
True. But before you let that go to your head...
就拿阿瑞克尼虫族来说
take the example of the Arachnids...
那是高度进化的社会
a highly evolved insect society.
以人类的标准来说它们的智慧很低
By human standards, they are relatively stupid...
它们却有数百万年的进化史
but their evolution stretches over millions of years...
- 现在 - 这儿 拿着
- and now... - Here, take this.
它们能够把胚种
they can colonize planets...
送入太空占领别的星球
by hurling their spore into space.
应该找到了
Okay, I think we got it.
这是心脏
That's the heart.
这是胃囊
And here's the stomach.
这算勇气十足?
Nerves of steel, huh?
(不符合)
别费力去想 凭你的直觉想像画面
Don't think about it. Just go on instinct.
试着将它形象化
Try to visualize it.
我看到黑桃A
I see the ace of spades.
统计学上的概率
You know, statistically speaking,
你知道就算瞎猜 到现在也该猜中了吧! !
you should have accidentally guessed right by now.
- 再试一次 - 我不会心灵感应 而且运气也很背
- Try another. - So my psychic abilities are zero and I'm unlucky.
这跟运气无关
No, luck's not a factor.
有些人就是特别灵敏
No one really knows why some people are sensitive and some aren't.
谁知道? 也许这是人类下一步的进化
Who knows? Maybe it's a new stage of human evolution.
所以才有这种研究
That's why they do these kind of Federal studies.
西哈诺 该死 暂停
What... Cyrano... Oh, shit. Time out.
它只是不甘寂寞
Oh, he just wants some attention.
你从不陪它玩
You don't play with him any more.
西哈诺...
Cyrano.
去烦我老妈去
Go bug Mom, Cyrano.
你是怎么做的?
How do you make him do that?
我让它觉得我妈脚上有食物
Oh, I gave him the impression there's a grub crawling up my mom's leg.
它非吃到不可
He's on a mission to go eat it.
滚开 别碰我
Ow! Oh! Get out! Get off my leg! Oh! Carl!
你最好别在我身上用心灵感应这招
I sure hope you don't do anything like that to me.
别怕 对人类我没辙...暂时不行
Don't be afraid. Can't do human. Yet.
好啊
Yeah!
好!
All right!
- 好啊! - 老虎队得分
- Yeah! Yeah! - Touchdown Tigers.
现在的比数是41比38
And the score is now 41-38.
老虎队领先 只胜两局
Tigers lead with 2.:46 remaining...
这里是布宜诺斯艾利斯球场
here at the Buenos Aires Sports Arena.
巨人队喊暂停
Time out Giants.
- 你还好吧? - 好多了
- Are you all right? - Much better.
- 现在 - 好
- Now. - Good.Yeah!
好 上啊!
All right! Way to go, team!
嗨 你的头盔
Hey! Your helmet.
球赛后你要干嘛?
So, what are you doing after the game?
大家都要参加舞会 你去吗?
Well, everyone's going to the dance, aren't you?
不清楚 今晚是我当平民的最后一夜
I don't know. It's my last night as a civilian.
- 上 12号! 冲! - 明天我就要去特雷斯卡瓦
- Come on, number 12! Let's go! - Ship out for Tereshkova tomorrow.
- 你要去星舰军校? - 嗯
- You're going to the Fleet Academy? - Uh-huh.
我也想去
That's where I want to go!
十二号 上场了
Come on, number 12! Let's play ball!
别打我女友的主意
Don't get any ideas about my girlfriend!
情场如战场
All is fair in love and war.
- 巨人队! 巨人队! - 强尼 加油
- Giants! Giants! - Johnny! Yeah!
嘿 好啊!
Hey, yeah!
巨人队以43分领先 离终场只剩4秒钟
Giants leading 43-41. Just over 42 seconds remaining.
艾文 拉森 挡住攻击
Irvin, Lathom, cover the rush.
派瑞做假动作 勃迪跑远点
Perry, fake left. Bertolli, you go long.
瑞哥 翻跳动作 懂吗?
Rico, flip six three hole. Got it? Hey, Rico?
- 嘿! - 什么?
- Hey! - What?
专心点 翻跳动作 懂吗?
You're drifting! Flip six, three hole, on one! Got it?
- 尽管把球传给我 蒂丝 - 准备好了?
- Just throw me the ball, Diz. - Ready? Break!
好! 走 走!
Yeah! Go, go, go!
好!
All right!
耶!
Yeah!
得分了 比赛结束
He's in there. It's over.
你一下子就长这么大了
Who said you could grow up so fast, huh?
妈 别这样
Mom, don't get mushy.
这是今天寄来的
This came for you today.
是你要的吧?
I presume, at your request.
我有很多朋友都要服役
A lot of my friends are doing Federal Service.
你不是想报名入伍吧?
Well, you're not thinking of applying?
你疯啦?
Have you lost your mind?
我就算是要挨鞭刑也不准你去自毁前程
I'd rather take ten lashes in Public Square than see you ruin your life.
这是志愿服役
It's a term of service.
不是从军
It's not a career.
我只想一个人出去...
I just want to get out on my own...
见识一下银河系风光
see the galaxy for a couple years.
强尼 当兵会死人的
Johnny, people get killed in the Federal Service.
是谁把你说动的? 是那个老师 对吧?
Who gave you this idea? It's that teacher, isn't it?
他叫什么? 你应该知道
What's his name? You know the one I'm talking about.
- 瑞斯加科先生 - 瑞斯加科?
- Mr Rasczak. - Rasczak?
这名字真可笑 法律应该...
Silly name. There should be a law against...
禁止学校召募新兵
using a school as a recruiting station.
瑞斯加科不会这么做
No, Rasczak doesn't do that at all.
其实他反对学生从军
He sort of discourages you.
那就好
Well, that's good.
你得上哈佛 没什么好说的
'Cause you're going to Harvard, and that's the end of it.
这是我的决定 不是你的
It's my decision, not yours.
- 是这样吗? - 别吵了
- Oh, is that how it is, huh? - Wait, you two.
我和你父亲要给你个惊喜
Uh, Dad and I have a surprise for you that will settle this.
你猜得到吗?
Can you guess what it is?
猜不到
No.
你想见识银河系风光
You wanted to see the galaxy?
到土星外环旅行如何?
How about a trip to the Outer Rings?
西格玛海滩
Zegema Beach. Huh?
我一直想去那儿
I've always wanted to go there.
很好 就这么说定了
Good, good. Then it's all settled.
别走开
Sure. Don't go away.
我想找瑞斯加科先生
I'm just gonna go see Mr Rasczak.
瑞哥 想跳舞吗?
Hey, Rico, do you want to dance?
蒂丝 我答应卡门
Actually, Diz, I promised Carmen...
真可惜 她不在
Aw, come on. Too bad for her if she's not around.
过了今晚...
You know, it's sad. After tonight, most of us...
我们恐怕不会再见面
probably won't see each other again.
你要替巴西队打球吗?
So, you still gonna play for Rio?
是呀 除非东京队要征召我
Yeah, looks like. Unless Tokyo lets me start.
谁抢到你就走运
Well, anyone who gets you is lucky.
我们怎么没成为一对?
Johnny, how come we never got together?
我们不能只当朋友吗?
Can't we just be friends, Diz?
好
Sure.
- 谢谢 - 晚上好
- Thank you. - Good night.
蒂丝 我想找瑞斯加科先生
Look, Diz, I want to talk to Mr Rasczak.
你最好赶快去
Well, you better hurry up if you want to catch him.
你对我最好
You're the best.
瑞斯加科先生
Mr Rasczak!
- 什么事? 瑞哥 - 我要谢谢你
- What is it, Rico? - I want to thank you.
我最喜欢你的课
Your class was the best one I had this year.
我只希望你能有所收获
Well, it's really not my job to please. I just hope you learned something.
我想入伍
Well, I want to join up.
我觉得我有成为公民的勇气
I think I got what it takes to be a citizen.
很好 去试吧
Good for you. Go find out.
这是我的决定我父母却反对
Well, my parents are against it.
我知道这是我的选择
And I know it's my choice.
我在想...
I was wondering...
你若是我 你会怎么做?
what would you do if you were me?
能决定自己的前程
Figuring things out for yourself...
才是真正的自由
is the only freedom anyone really has.
珍惜这自由
Use that freedom.
自己决定吧
Make up your own mind, Rico.
别乱讲
Don't exaggerate.
是真的 你的眼睛好美
I'm serious. I think you have really beautiful eyes.
- 你了解? - 强尼
- You know? - Johnny.
这是山德
Uh, this is Zander.
我们在球场上较过劲
Yeah, we know each other from the game.
- 你不介意吧? - 不介意 我们赢了
- No hard feelings? - No, none at all. We won.
来吧 卡门 最后一支舞
Come on, Carmen. It's the last dance.
也许我在军校会见到你
Well, maybe I'll see you at the Academy.
是啊 也许会吧
Yeah. Who knows?
- 祝你好运 - 山德也要当飞行员
- Good luck. - Zander's going for pilot too.
你们真是绝配 卡门
You two have so much in common.
强尼·瑞哥 你在吃醋吗?
Johnny Rico, are you jealous?
也许吧
Well, maybe.
你不必吃醋
You don't have to be jealous.
嗨 嗨...快分开 你们两个
Hey, hey, break it up, you two.
要亲热就到别的地方
There's a place for that sort of thing.
我考虑好了 我要入伍
I've been thinking, and I'm gonna do it, Carmen.
我要加入联邦军队
I'm gonna go for Federal Service.
太好了
That's great.
我和卡尔明天登记 和我们一起去吧
Carl and I are signing up tomorrow. Come with us.
我会的
I will.
我父亲今晚不在家
My father's not home tonight.
我了解从军的...
I do now, of my own free will...
意义和义务
after having been duly advised and warned...
这一切完全出于自愿
of the meaning and consequences of this oath...
我至少
enrol in the Federal Service...
必须服役两年
for not less than two years...
若是有需要...
and as much longer as may be required...
我愿继续效忠部队
by the needs of the Federation.
- 完了? - 谢谢
- All set? - Thank you.
又来一批新兵
Fresh meat for the grinder, eh?
- 你们的成绩如何? - 我要当飞行员
- So, how'd you kids do? - I'm gonna be a pilot.
很好 我们很需要飞行员
Well, good for you. We need all the pilots we can get.
- 你被分派到研发部门吗? - 没有
- Hey, did you get starside R and D? - No.
- 不是吧? - 我要到战略理论部
- I don't believe it. - I got Games and Theory.
战略理论?
Games and Theory?
- 那是军事情报部 - 嗯
- That's military intelligence. - Yeah.
好家伙 卡尔
Way to go, Carl.
下次见面我就得向你敬礼
Next time we meet, I'll probably have to salute you.
嗯
Hmm.
你呢 孩子?
How about you, son?
- 机动部队 长官 - 很好
- Infantry, sir. - Good for you.
机动部队让我成为现在这样的男子汉
Mobile Infantry made me the man I am today.
新兵必须在二十四小时内...
All recruits must report to the Federal Transportation Hub...
到联邦运送站报到
within 24 hours.
欢迎加入联邦军队的行列
Welcome to the adventure of Federal Service.
咱们一起发誓
Let's make a vow.
不管怎样 我们永远是朋友
No matter what, we'll always be friends.
我同意
I'll go for that.
我们恐怕不会再见面
Well, chances are we'll never see each other again.
分隔几百万光年的距离
We'll be millions of light-years away from each other.
不过 好呀 有何不可?
But, uh, yeah, sure. Why not?
你给我去办退役
You'll resign, and that's all there is to it.
虽然很没面子 不过也只能这样了
It may look bad, but if that's the worst you suffer, then that's fine.
- 我不要退役 - 你一定要
- I won't quit! - I'm telling you, you will.
你不能入伍 你要去渡假
You're not going back. You're going on vacation!
我不去渡假
I am not going on vacation!
我要当公民
I want to be a citizen.
这是我的决定
It's my decision. I made it.
你走出去找就不认你这儿子
You walk out that door, you are cut off, young man.
懂吗?
You understand me?
好吧 我不要你了
All right, that's it! You are cut off!
你这是何必呢?
Johnny, why won't you change your mind?
当公民这么重要吗?
Does citizenship mean that much to you?
当然重要
Well, yeah, sure.
希望如此
Well, I hope so.
希望你别为了穿帅制服的...
I hope you don't ruin your life over some silly little girl...
女孩而自毁前程
who wants to look handsome in a uniform.
- 别这么说卡门 - 强尼
- Don't talk about Carmen that way! - Johnny.
听到什么吗?
Do you have everything?
好
Great.
强尼
Johnny
- 你迟到了 - 我父亲帮我收拾行李
- You're late. - My dad had to help me pack.
他怕再也见不到我
Suddenly he's afraid he's never gonna see me again or something.
他真好 不过很费时间
It was sweet, but it took forever.
我猜我准备好了
Oh. Anyway, I guess I'm ready to go.
我也是 我只剩这身衣服
Yeah, me too. I'm wearing everything I own.
我很遗憾你的父母反对
I'm sorry your parents were mad.
管它呢 反正...
Who cares? The Federation will give me...
这两年军队会养我 对吧?
everything I need for the next two years, right?
- 你和卡尔联络过吗? - 有 他早上就走了
- You talk to Carl? - Yeah, he left this morning.
- 他不能说去哪里 - 能够入伍我好兴奋
- Couldn't say where. - Oh, it's exciting, going away.
我也很害怕 你不会吗?
But I'm scared. Aren't you?
我会很想你
I'm gonna miss you.
我也会想你
I'm gonna miss you too.
我爱你
I love you.
前往特雷斯卡瓦的新兵准备启程
Outbound group 94B to Tereshkova...
我该走了
That's me.
说一次 试试看
Just say it once. Try it on for size.
我爱你
I love you.
别忘了写信给我
Don't forget to write.
我不会忘的
I won't.
(联邦电视网)
(世界团结一致)
全自动步枪 谁想拿?
Fully automatic Morita. Who wants to hold it?
我! 我! 我...
Me! Me! Me! Me! Me!
公民万岁 人民创造美好明天
Citizen rule. People making a better tomorrow.
(你想知道更多吗?)
杀人犯今天被捕后接受审判
A murderer was captured this morning and tried today.
有罪
Guilty.
处以死刑
Sentence.: death.
今晚六点行刑 实况转播
Execution tonight at 6.:00. All net. All channels.
(你想知道更多吗?)
(你能心灵感应吗?)
如果你觉得能
If you think you're psychic,
也许是真的
maybe you are.
各地都在进行这项研究
Federal studies are being conducted in your community.
(你想知道更多吗?)
每个小学生都知道阿瑞克尼虫很危险
Every school kid knows that Arachnids are dangerous.
(不宜观赏)
摩门教徒却罔顾联邦警告
However, Mormon extremists disregarded Federal warnings...
在虫族隔离区建立教会
and established Fort Joe Smith deep inside the Arachnid Quarantine Zone.
不料该地区早就被别人占领
Too late, they realized that Dantana had already been chosen by other colonists.:
阿瑞克尼虫族
Arachnids.
(你想知道更多吗?)
- 一 二 三 四! - 你们大半都...
- One, two, three, four! - Most of you will not...
熬不过魔鬼训练
live to be in the Mobile Infantry.
因为你们都不够强
The trouble is, you are not good enough the way you are.
手放好
Hands at your side!
抬头挺胸
Chin up.
我是你们的教官辛姆中士
I am your senior drill instructor, Career Sergeant Zim!
小腹缩紧 双腿并拢
Suck in that gut! Feet together!
我真是衰毙了
To think this had to happen to me.
一群蠢蛋 算了
What a bunch of apes. No, strike that!
你们逊毙了
You don't rate that good.
我没见过...
Never in my life have I seen...
你觉得很好笑?
Do you think I'm funny? Do I make you laugh?
- 你觉得我是小丑吗? - 对不起
- Do you think I'm a comedian, son? - I'm sorry.
你们随时都要尊称我为长官
The first words and the last words out of your stinking holes will be "Sir"!
- 明白吗? - 明白 长官
- Do you get me? - Sir, yes, sir!
绕着军营跑一圈
You see that armoury? Run around it.
我叫你跑就跑
Run, I said! Run, run, run!
- 布隆斯基 跟他跑! - 快! 快!
- Bronski, keep pace! - Move! Move!
如果你们觉得我太狠太不公平
Now, anytime you think I'm being too tough...
或是开始想念老妈
anytime you think I'm being unfair...
那就马上退出
anytime you miss your mommy, quit!
填好表格 签名 打包
You sign form 1240-A, you grab your gear...
走上失败者的路
you take a stroll down Washout Lane!
明不明白?
Do you get me?
- 明白 长官! - 可悲
- Sir, yes, sir! - Pathetic!
全是一群孬种 不知道这里有没有好汉
I wonder if there's a handful of guts in the whole bunch of you.
谁认为他有办法打倒我?
Now, who here thinks they got what it takes to knock me down?
我觉得我能 长官
Sir! I guess maybe I do, sir!
哦! 天哪! 天哪!
Ow! God! God!
- 你没事吧? - 没事 长官
- You all right, son? - Sir, yes, sir!
我的手好像断了
It's my arm. I think it's broken, sir.
- 医官! - 天哪
- Medic! - God.
痛是心里想的
Pain is in your mind!
- 下一个是谁? - 长官
- Who's next? - Sir!
新兵弗洛斯报到 长官
Recruit Flores reporting for duty, sir!
你特别要求转到这单位?
You specifically requested transfer from Fort Cronkite to this training unit?
我听说这里是最严格的
Sir, I heard it was the best, sir!
的确是最严格
It is the best.
你凭什么以为自己够资格?
But what makes you think you're good enough?
这女孩有种当班长
Now that's the kind of gal who makes squad leader.
我才要当班长
That's my job you're talking about.
我很想宰了辛姆中士
You know, I'd like to kill that Sergeant Zim.
- 你的态度很不好 - 小心
- Whoa, improper attitude! - Watch it.
- 这样会被踢出去 - 再见吧
- They'll kick you out for talking like that. - Bye-bye.
你肯定会走上失败走路
There you go down Washout Lane.
没种就是没种
Yup, you either got what it takes, or you don't.
- 我们在排队 - 你也要等 王牌
- Hey, there is a line. - Wait your turn, Ace.
别紧张 小兵 反正菜都很烂
Hey, at ease, little soldier. It's all the same muck.
乖乖去排队
Get in line like everyone else.
你这阔少爷真有种
You got some guts for a rich kid.
咱们交个朋友 如何?
I guess you and me could be buddies. What do you say?
- 真是荣幸 - 当然 我最够朋友了
- I'm honoured. - Hey! Of course you are.
每个人都应该有个像我这样的朋友
Everybody should have a friend like me.
王牌 到后面排队吧
Come on, Ace. Back of the line now! Back of the line!
- 真是个混蛋 - 讨厌鬼
- What a jerk, man. - Tough guy.
瑞哥 跟我一起吃饭
Hey, Rico, want to sit together?
不 谢了
No thanks, Diz.
你有什么问题?
What's your malfunction, Rico?
你就是问题
You are.
我想一个人入伍 你却硬要跟来
I joined up to get out on my own, and you had to tag along.
你以为我为你入伍?
You think I joined the Mobile Infantry because of you?
你敢说不是?
You saying you didn't?
嗨
Hi.
想都别想 王牌 你不行的
Forget about it, Ace. You don't stand a chance.
难道你就能当班长?
What makes you even think you're gonna make squad leader, Rico?
- 我比你有料 - 哈!
- Something I got, you don't. - Ha!
- 有钱少爷只会装阔 - 才不
- You rich kids are all the same. - It isn't about that.
- 这得靠能力 - 嘿!
- It's about who's the best. - Hey!
第三班
Third squad!
长官 我不懂
Sir, I don't understand.
在核战争中何必用刀?
Who needs a knife in a nuke fight, anyway?
只要按下按钮就行 长官
All you gotta do is push a button, sir.
暂停 手放在墙上 伞兵
Cease fire. Put your hand on that wall, trooper.
把手放在墙上
Put your hand on that wall!
该死
Damn it.
敌人的手掌受伤就不能按钮
The enemy cannot push a button if you disable his hand.
医官
Medic!
我们有一个共同点
Ah, well, we all have one thing in common.
我们都蠢到要参加机动部队
We were all stupid enough to sign up for Mobile Infantry.
- 布雷肯瑞奇 你为何加入? - 我全家都是农夫
- Breckinridge, what's your excuse? - Oh, my family's all farmers.
我讨厌务农 而机动部队...
I hate farming. I mean, uh, Mobile Infantry...
比起来就像是在野餐
It's like pure picnic by comparison.
乡巴佬真是又蠢又壮对不对?
All right, so they grow 'em big and dumb on the farm planet, huh?
- 而且帅! - 我就爱壮汉
- And pretty! - I like big!
- 蒂嘉娜 你呢? - 我想要从政
- Djana'D, what about you? - Oh, I'm going in for politics...
想从政就得成为公民
and, you know, you gotta be a citizen for that.
- 所以我就来了 - 你想负起责任
- So here I am. - Ah, you want some responsibility.
- 对 - 苏杰米 接着说吧
- Yeah. - Shujimi, come on, let's keep it goin'.
我被哈佛大学取录
I got into Harvard, but my father says forget it.
可是我老爸嫌学费太贵
It's gonna cost an arm and a leg, you know?
只要服役
So, if I serve,
就能赚取学费
Federation pays my way.
我想生孩子
I want to have babies.
公民比较容易申请执照
You know, it's a lot easier to get a licence if you've served.
- 然后呢... - 我要当职业军官
- So... - I'm going career.
按步就班升上去
Officer's training. All the way.
未来的星际元帅 瑞哥 该你了
Future Sky Marshal. All right, Rico, your turn.
不要多管闲事
Who asked you to be so nosy?
怎么? 我是坏人吗? 我想当作家
What? I'm the-the bad guy? I'm gonna be a writer, you know?
当然能管闲事
A writer's got a right to be nosy.
弗洛雷斯 你和瑞哥都来自布宜诺斯艾利斯
Hey, Flores, you know Rico from Buenos Aires.
- 他为什么入伍? - 哦
- What's his story? - Oh, uh,
他是为了一个女孩子
he's here because of a girl.
瑞哥 大情圣
Oh, Rico! Lover boy!
- 他让我感到兴奋 - 他一定会打你
- He's getting me excited. - He's gonna blow.
为了你吗?
Is it you?
这是我们的宿舍 很简陋 不过是我的家
This is where we live. It's not much, but it's home.
这是我的床铺 我每晚都梦到你
Right there, that's my bunk, where I dream about you every night.
训练很辛苦
Boot's pretty tough.
有时我很灰心
Sometimes I think I won't make it.
不过我一想到你就会更努力
But then I think about what you're doing, and I try harder.
- 嘿 你介意吗? - 努力点 宝贝
- Hey, guys! Do you mind? - Try harder, baby, try harder!
谁知道? 也许我会成为班长
Who knows? They might even make me squad leader.
我得上床了
Uh-oh, I better pack it in.
我爱你 宝贝 我爱你!
Oh, I love you, baby, I love you!
- 写信给我 - 我是如此爱你
- Write me! - I love you so much
- 我要杀了你 - 我是如此爱你
- I'm gonna kill you guys! - I love you so much
- 再见 记得写信 - 再见!
- Bye! Write me. - Bye!
五分钟后绕行月球 艾邦妮兹
Orbit in five, Ibanez.
先到先飞
First one there gets to fly.
- 关闭舱门 - 等一下
- Locking it down. - Wait! Wait!
别让艾邦妮兹驾驶 她太疯狂了
Oh, no. Not Ibanez again. She's crazy!
准备 发射
Ready, go!
好!
Yeah!
伸出机翼
Deploying wings.
你干嘛这么开心?
How come you're in such a good mood, huh?
今天我要开战舰
'Cause today I get to fly that.
飞行受训人员艾邦妮兹报到
Pilot Trainee Ibanez reporting for duty, ma'am.
坐在副驾驶座
Take the number two chair, Ibanez.
- 是的 女士 - 看见啦?
- Yes, ma'am. - You see that?
- 辨识身份 - 艾邦妮兹 T-325-A 正确
- Identify. - Ibanez, T-325-A, clear.
你在这儿干嘛?
What are you doing here?
我要教你驾驶这艘战舰
I'm the guy whose gonna teach you to fly this crate.
助理教官
Oh, Assistant Instructor.
我该尊称你长官吗?
Should I call you "sir"?
- 我下命令才要 - 准备起飞
- Only when I give you an order. - Prepare for departure.
没想到我们会再见面
It's amazing, us running into each other like this.
- 也许是命中注定 - 也许不是
- Maybe it's fate. - Maybe not.
我听说有个女孩很优秀
Heard about this crazy girl coming through the Academy.
她是天生好手 只是有点野
Solid math, a little wild on the stick, but a natural.
我知道是你
And when it turned out to be you,
就安排和你见面
I just made sure that we would run into each other.
杨罗杰号可以起飞
Rodger Young cleared for undocking and departure.
好了 艾邦妮兹
All right, Ibanez.
- 开出去吧 - 是的 女士
- Take her out. - Yes, ma'am.
系统正常
All systems go.
进行模拟飞行时老师都跟不上我
In simulation, my supervisors could never keep up.
这不是模拟飞行
Well, this isn't simulation any more...
小心点 军校生
so take her out easy, cadet.
是的 长官
Yes, sir.
距离五米
Five metres from object.
距离三米
Three metres from object.
通过
Clear.
- 别超过起飞速限 - 否则呢?
- Don't exceed port speed. - Or what?
你的飞行权会被取消 还有我的
Or they revoke your flight status, and mine.
你的前途掌握在我手上
Your career is in my hands.
慢慢来 副驾驶
Steady as she goes, Number Two.
- 准备超光速飞行 - 是的
- Prepare for warp. - Yes, ma'am.
一号 计算木星航道
Number One, design for Jupiter orbit.
准备转换超光速引擎
All crew, all sections, stand by to cut in C-drive.
五...四...
Star drive in five, four...
准备 稳定...
ready, steady...
启动
go!
快进攻 快!
We're going in! Move!
我们冲不破防线
Man, they're defended. No way in.
- 翻跳动作 - 什么?
- Flip six, three hole. - What?
你做翻跳动作就能得分
You run a flip six, three hole play, and you can score.
- 掩护我 - 好
- Cover me. - You got it.
上吧
Now!
- 谢了 哥们 - 杂种
- Thanks, buddy. - Bastard!
嗯!
Yeah!
那小子很灵活
Kid's got some moves.
让他当班长 看看他的能耐
Give him a squad. See what he can do.
小猫咪
Kitty, Kitty.
我得教你们打台球
Someone's got to teach you guys how to play some pool here.
瞧他
Look at him.
那副得意样 真自傲
Have you ever seen anybody so pleased with himself?
辛姆一定得选个乖乖牌
Well, Zim must have had to choose someone to be his brownnose.
没有你我就办不到
I couldn't have done it without you, Diz.
朋友?
Friends?
朋友
Friends.
- 信来了 李维 - 我就是
- Mail call! Levy! - Yeah, that's me.
- 苏杰米 - 在
- Shujimi! - Here.
- 瑞哥 - 在
- Rico. - Here.
- 布雷肯瑞奇 - 嗯 在
- Breckinridge! - Yeah, right here.
- 泰勒 - 我在这儿
- Niler. - Yeah, here I am. Ah, great, my dad.
没了 大伙
That's all, folks.
嗨 强尼
Hi, Johnny.
抱歉没早点写信给你
I'm sorry I haven't written you sooner, but, uh...
噢...瑞哥 你配不上她
Oh, Rico,it's been really busy.you don't deserve that!
- 嘘 嘘 - 他们真的在这里
- Shh, shh. - They've really got us going here.
你一定当上班长
They must have made you squad leader by now.
没有的话 叫他们来找我
And if they haven't, tell 'em to talk to me.
你瞧 找到好女人就不用愁
See? All it takes is the love of a good woman.
- 看这儿 - 别看了
- Look at that.Look at those. - Stop it.
不是很美吗?
Isn't it beautiful?
我好爱这儿
I love it out here.
这就是问题
That's also the problem
因为 我想当职业军人
Because I think I'm gonna go career.
我要指挥战舰
I want to command a ship of my own.
这样一来...
And you know...
我们就没时间
I don't think that's gonna leave a lot of room...
交往 强尼
for you and me, Johnny.
我知道你会很失望
I know that's not what you wanted to hear.
可是
But, uh...
我得把握机会 对不起
I have to follow my heart. I'm sorry.
写信给我
Write me, all right?
让我们永远当好朋友
Write me so that I know we'll always be friends.
- 让我们回到游戏 - 我觉得很对不起强尼
- Let's get back to the game. - I feel so sorry for Johnny.
她们总是伤透你的心
Funny how they always want to be friends...
之后还想做好朋友
after they rip your guts out, huh?
我是活该
Yeah. Well, it's what I deserve.
什么意思?
What are you talking about?
我会入伍全是为了她
Oh, I joined up for her.
没有她我就不会来
I wouldn't even be here if it wasn't for her.
你在说什么? 你是靠自己当上班长
What are you talking about? You made squad leader on your own.
至少你还有我差遣
And, hey, you still got me to kick around.
好日子结束了
Fun and games are over, children.
今天要进行
You will be firing live ammunition...
实弹的模拟战斗
in a simulated combat environment.
你们千万要小心进行
You will exercise extreme caution on my assault course!
- 你们都明白了吗? - 明白 长官
- Do you get me? - Sir, yes, sir!
瑞哥 带队出去
Rico, take 'em out!
第一组跟我来 第二组十秒钟后出发
First fire team with me. Next team in ten seconds.
最高分是180
Maximum score has been 2 80.
- 你们一定要更好 - 上吧
- I expect you to do better! - Go!
苏杰米 趴下来
Shujimi, stay down!
该死 布雷肯瑞奇 别挡住我
Hey! Goddam it, Breckinridge, clear my line of fire!
我的头盔坏了
It's my helmet! It's all screwed up!
你会碍事的
You're gonna blow the score!
- 蠢蛋 - 妈的!
- Damn! - Dumb shit!
快前进 怎么了?
Diz, stay put! What's the problem?
- 头盔有问题 - 给我
- Damn thing keeps getting in my way! - Give it to me.
每次出错都是你的问题
How come whenever something goes wrong, it's always you, Breckinridge?
那是因为我又蠢又壮
It must be 'cause I'm big and dumb!
没错
Yeah, right!
医官
Medic!
瑞哥 你被解除班长职位
Rico, you are relieved of squad command!
是你准许新兵脱下头盔吗?
Rico, did you give the recruit permission to remove his helmet?
是的 长官 布雷肯瑞奇说他的头盔坏了
Sir, yes, sir. Breckinridge reported a helmet malfunction...
我要他拿给我看
and I asked him to show it to me, sir.
你会修理M-3型头盔吗?
Are you rated to repair the M-3 Tactical Helmet, Rico?
不会 长官
Sir, no, sir!
那么你为何在实弹演习时...
Then why did you order your man to remove his helmet...
叫他脱下头盔?
during a live fire exercise?
我需要每名队员尽全力
Sir, I needed everyone in my squad operational, sir!
我想要获胜 长官
I wanted to win, sir!
继续
Carry on.
军士 我们因为此事失去两名新兵
Sergeant, we've already lost two recruits over this incident.
你认为这个人还有前途吗?
Do you think there's any possibility of salvaging this man?
有的 长官
Yes, sir, I do.
好吧
All right.
让他接受行政处罚
We'll try administrative punishment.
囚犯 站住
Prisoner, halt!
用力咬
Bite down on this, son.
很有用 我很清楚
It helps. I know.
因为他指挥无能
For incompetence of command...
在实弹演习中...
for failure to abide by safety regulations...
违反安全规定...
during a live fire exercise...
因为他的疏失导致一名士兵死亡
for negligence which contributed to the death of a teammate...
新兵强尼·瑞哥
recruit trainee John Rico...
必须受刑...
is sentenced to administrative punishment.
十下鞭刑
Ten lashes.
开始行刑
You may carry out the sentence.
一...
One!
二...
Two!
三...
Three!
四...
Four!
五...
Five!
六...
Six!
七...
Seven!
八...
Eight!
九...
Nine!
十!
Ten!
谢了 你猜中我的心意
Thanks. You read my mind.
下半夜更最难熬
Oh, third watch always seems to last forever.
不一定
I don't know.
这得看你和谁一起值班
It depends on who you're spending it with.
出了问题
Something's wrong.
- 那儿 - 我重新设定航道
- There. - No, I replotted the course.
- 这样更有效率 - 你才来了三个星期...
- It's more efficient this way. - Three weeks aboard a starship...
就想跟我比?
and you think that you can lick my navs?
尽管查
Check it.
我和达拉第舰长谈过
You know, I was talking with Captain Deladier...
她说...
and, uh, she said...
别转移话题
Don't change the subject.
我对不对?
Am I right?
"新航道最佳" 你做得对
Yeah. Yeah. You're right.
那么舰长怎么说?
So, what did the captain say?
她说我们应该正式搭档...
She thinks that we ought to team up officially...
为她服务
and crew for her.
- 你和我? - 我们是好搭档 卡门
- You and me, huh? - We're good together, Carmen.
各方面都领先
We're way ahead of the curve in every department.
我们很有默契
I can anticipate you.
你知道我要什么
You know what I want.
我不知道 你要什么?
No. What do you want?
太空中有重力场
There's a gravity field out there.
- 进行扫瞄 启动 - 那儿
- Run a scan. Sensors on. - There.
- 重力2.25 继续增加... - 报告
- Gravity at 225 and rising. - Report.
船长 前方有不明物体
Captain, we're in the path of an unidentified object...
向我们快速冲来...
moving toward us at high speed.
根据资料应该是小行星
Profile suggests an asteroid, ma'am.
(撞击警告)
- 六秒后撞击 - 紧急闪躲动作
- Impact, six seconds! - Emergency evasion!
三...二...
Three, two,
启动
fire!
关闭21号舱门
Close compartment 21!
从哪儿来的?
Where'd it come from?
从虫族隔离区来的
It came out of the Arachnid Quarantine Zone, ma'am.
通讯官通知舰队小行星接近中
Number Four, contact Fleet. Tell 'em there's a loose asteroid headed their way.
通讯失效 全都被摧毁
Communications are down, ma'am. They're gone.
- 估计损失 - 舰身受损
- Damage assessment. - Hull's compromised.
我们没死掉真走运
We're lucky to be alive, ma'am.
这不是靠运气
Luck didn't have anything to do with it.
我们的飞行小组很优秀
We have a hell of a flight team.
你不能离开
It really stinks, you going.
机动部队没有我也一样
Yeah, well, the Mobile Infantry will just have to get along without me.
我不懂 瑞哥 你接受了惩罚
I don't get it, Rico. You took your licks.
如果他们不想要你 可以把你踢走
If they didn't want you, they would have kicked you out.
嘿...
Hey...
我不该入伍 我害死人...
I joined up for the wrong reasons. I got a guy killed.
这就证明我没有能力
I figure that kind of proves I don't have what it takes.
瑞哥 电话接通了
Rico, your call's going through.
去接
Take it there.
- 喂? 强尼 - 嗨 妈妈
- Hello? Oh, Johnny! - Hi, Mom.
比尔 快接电话 是强尼
B-Bill, pick it up. It's Johnny!
- 强尼? - 爸爸
- Johnny? - Dad.
- 你的制服呢? - 比尔...
- Where's your uniform? - Bill.
见到你真好
It's just good to hear from you.
你好吗? 儿子?
How are you, son?
我不适合这里 爸爸
It's not really working out here for me, Dad.
我在想...
I was thinking...
不知道我能不能回家
I was hoping it would be all right if I came home.
当然能 马上回来
Well, of-of course. You should come home immediately.
对不起 我太傻了
I'm sorry. I've been an idiot.
别这么说 你先回家...
Don't talk like that. You just come on home...
咱们再好好谈谈
talk things out.
我们很爱你 儿子
We love you, son.
- 那是什么? - 好像要下雨
- My, what's that? - Looks like rain.
- 这时候? - 外面好暗
- This time of year? - Sure is dark.
大气干扰导致...
Your transmission has been terminated...
通讯中断
due to atmospheric interference.
请稍后再试
Please try your call again later.
再见了
Well, see ya.
你就这样退出...
Hey, you take that stroll down Washout Lane...
只证明一件事
you're only proving one thing,Johnny.
什么事?
What's that, Diz?
你没有资格当公民
That you don't have what it takes to be a citizen.
什么事?
What's happening?
嗨 发生什么事?
Hey, hey, what's going on?
发生什么事?
Wh-What's going on?
- 嗨 Kitten 怎么回事? - 战争 我们要去参战了...
- Hey, Kitten, what's going on? - It's war! We're going to war!
这次的灾难前所未有
The devastation we are seeing is unparalleled.
根据估计有数百万人丧命 一座城市全毁
Judging from early estimates, millions dead, a city in ruins.
那是日内瓦吗?
Is that Geneva?
强尼 是该死的大虫攻击我们
Goddam bugs whacked us, Johnny.
虫族从大本营克兰达夫星球...
The meteor was shot out of orbit by bug plasma...
发射电浆把陨石撞离轨道
that derived from Klendathu, the Arachnids'home planet.
这个曾被称为拉丁乐园的城市片瓦不留
Nothing lives in what was once called the Latin Paradise.
强尼 那是我们...
Oh,Johnny, it's us.
布宜诺斯艾利斯完全消失
Buenos Aires has been wiped off the Earth.
...我们的家
That's home.
刚才联邦委员会一致表决...
The Federal Council met moments ago and voted unanimously...
全体动员消灭虫族大敌
for mobilization to destroy the Arachnid threat.
(8764608人死亡)
- 我是认真的 我要去 - 辛姆 你得留下来
- I'm serious. I'll go anywhere. - Forget it, Zim. We need you here.
- 我要打仗 - 只有一种方法能让你去打仗...
- I want combat, sir. - The only way you're gonna see combat...
被降为二等兵!
is if you bust yourself to private!
- 明白? - 我明白 长官
- Get me? - Yes, sir, I get you.
- 长官 - 你要做什么? 瑞哥
- Sir! - What do you want, Rico?
我要收回退出的要求
I wish to reconsider my request to drop out, sir.
你已经签好表格
You already signed your 1240-A, son.
- 那是非法的 - 少校 我不该退出
- It wouldn't be legal. - Major, I know it was wrong.
我没吸取教训 反而又犯错
I didn't learn from one mistake, and I made another, sir.
你做出决定
You made your decision, son.
长官 我全家都在布宜诺斯艾利斯
Sir, my family, my whole family, was in Buenos Aires, sir.
瑞哥 这是你的签名吗?
Is this your signature, Rico?
是的 长官
Sir, yes, it is, sir!
看起来不像
Doesn't look like it to me.
- 去吧 二等兵 - 是的 长官
- Carry on, Private! - Yes, sir!
(联邦电视网)
(战争)
看到布宜诺斯艾利斯市的残骸先是悲痛
Out of the ashes of Buenos Aires comes first sorrow...
接下来是愤怒
then anger.
只有死虫才是好虫子
The only good bug is a dead bug.
联邦委员会在日内瓦开会
In Geneva, the Federal Council convenes.
我们必须誓死...
We must meet the threat with our valour, our blood...
勇敢面对挑战
indeed, with our very lives...
捍卫人类文明
to ensure that human civilization, not insect...
别让虫族永远统治银河系
dominates this galaxy, now and always!
狄恩元帅...
Sky Marshal Dienes announces plans...
向虫族陨石来源...
for an offensive against Klendathu...
克兰达夫星球宣战
source of the bug meteor that destroyed Buenos Aires.
(你想知道更多吗?)
联邦科学家每天不断研究新方法消灭虫族
Every day, Federal scientists are looking for new ways to kill bugs.
一般的虫族战士很笨...
Your basic Arachnid warrior isn't too smart...
可是打断它的一只脚...
but you can blow off a limb...
它却能保留八成战斗力
and it's still 86 percent combat effective.
有一个窍门: 瞄准神经干 把它撂倒
Here's a tip.:Aim for the nerve stem, and put it down for good.
(你想知道更多吗?)
人人都出力 你呢
Everyone's doing their part. Are you?
战争需要每个人贡献力量
Die! Die! The war effort needs your effort...
家庭 工作和社区...
at work, at home, in your community.
(胜利倒数)
这里是...
We now break net and take you live...
位于虫族隔离区的...
to Fleet Battle Station Ticonderoga...
提康德鲁加星际战舰基地
deep inside the Arachnid Quarantine Zone...
英勇的星舰战将准备出击
where the men and women of the Federal Armed Services prepare to attack.
准备连线...开始
D XQ uplink on two, one. You're on.
这里没人知道何时开始...
No one here in the AQZ knows exactly...
进攻克兰达夫星
when the invasion of Klendathu will occur.
大家都在猜
But everyone's talking about it...
觉得也许是明天
and the talk says tomorrow.
看来机动部队想大嚼虫族
Here's a bunch of MI kids that look like they could eat bugs for lunch.
- 好吃 好吃 好吃 - 大兵
- Yum, yum, yum. - So, trooper,
你不怕大虫吗?
you're not too worried about fighting the Arachnids?
只要发射一枚核弹 大虫就死翘翘
Hey, shoot a nuke down a bug hole, you got a lot of dead bugs.
希望全炸死之前 我能打死几只虫
Am I right? I just hope it's not over before we get some.
- 得了 - 有人说虫族生态...
- Okay, come on. - Some say the bugs were provoked...
遭到了破坏才对人类反击
by the intrusion of humans into their natural habitat...
我们该和平共处不该对虫族开战
that a "live and let live policy" is preferable to war with the bugs.
我告诉你
Let me tell you something.
我是布宜诺斯艾利斯市人 我要消灭它们
I'm from Buenos Aires, and I say kill them all!
- 对 - 继续
- Yeah! - Go on,Yeah!
- 对! - 对啊!
- Yeah! - Oh, yeah!
狠角色
Big bad bugs, huh?
咱们要去纹身
Hey, guys, we ought to get tattoos.
- 一起去吧 - 好
- Hey, let's all get cut together. - Yeah.
- 纹身干嘛? - 什么?
- What do I want a tattoo for? - Oh, what?
你的皮肤太嫩吗?
Your skin's too pretty? Come on, everybody's doing it.
强尼
Hey,Johnny!
强尼·瑞哥
Johnny Rico.
卡门
Carmen?
稍息
Oh. At ease.
我休假 最好别戴军帽
Guess I ought to lose the hat when I'm off duty.
- 嗨 蒂丝 - 卡门
- Hi, Diz. - Carmen.
我妈说得对
My mother was right about you.
你穿制服很好看
You look great in a uniform.
你也挺帅的
You look pretty good yourself.
你有什么消息?
So, what do you hear?
布宜诺斯艾利斯有没有人生还?
You know about anyone who made it out of BA alive?
我试着不多想
Most of the time I don't think about it.
假装是别人的事
Like it happened to someone else.
可是突然觉醒时就哭个不停
Then it hits me, and I, uh, can't stop crying.
我们还活着 这值得高兴
Well, we're still alive. Got to be happy about that.
你看到我好像不高兴
You don't look very happy to see me.
我该高兴吗?
Should I be?
强尼 现在不同 我们在打仗
Johnny, it's different now. We're at war.
我们分开对你我都好
I mean, I think what I did was probably the best thing for both of us.
没事吧 中尉?
Everything copacetic, Lieutenant?
山德 记得强尼吗?
Zander, you remember Johnny.
我和山德是飞行搭档
Zander and I are a flight team now.
舰队最好的小组
Yeah, and we're best in the fleet.
我懂了
I get it.
这样对你我最好
This is the part that's best for both of us.
- 别再装了... - 强尼 等等
- Don't do me any more favours. - Johnny, wait.
算了 他是机动部队
No, forget it, Lieutenant. He's Mobile Infantry.
他们只会杀人
See, when you're trained to kill...
不懂得礼貌
it just doesn't pay to be polite.
你对机动部队有意见吗?
You got something to say about the Mobile Infantry?
你听得很清楚
I think you heard me.
你想打架吗 二等兵?
You want to make something of it, Private?
我不跟军官打架
Not with an officer. No, sir.
- 机动部队不是蠢蛋 - 我就撇开官阶
- The MI doesn't mint stupid troopers. - Well, let's disregard rank.
山德 别这样
Zander, please.
听到吗? 这无关官阶
Everybody hear that? Rank is not an issue here.
- 别这样 - 他敢怎样?
- Don't do this. - Come on. What's he gonna do?
来呀 臭大兵!
Come on, jarheads!
我要宰了你
Let go of me! Come on! I'm gonna kill you!
我要你好看
I'm gonna kill you! I'll kill you!
住手 快
Guys! Guys! Quit it! Come on! Come on!
- 他不值得 - 快 快
- He's not worth it! - Come on! Come on!
瑞哥 算了 机动部队和舰队一向不合
Forget it, Rico! Mobile Infantry and Fleet don't mix. Come on.
来吧 走吧
Come on, let's go.
臭大兵
Jarheads.
- 机动部队万岁 - 耶!
- Mobile Infantry rules! - Yeah!
痛死了
Oh, God, that hurts.
我有办法让你更痛
Hey, well, I got something that might hurt just a little bit more, buddy.
我们要打仗 一定会赢
Oh, yeah! We're gonna fight, and we're gonna win!
(死神降临)
我是舰长
This is the captain speaking.
全体人员准备降落
All personnel prepare for drop.
倒数三分钟
We are at D-minus three and counting.
我们是先锋部队
We are going in with first wave.
敌人最多
Means more bugs for us to kill.
彻底消灭敌区
You smash the entire area.
杀死所有长两只脚以上的东西
You kill anything that has more than two legs.
- 明白吗? - 我们明白 长官
- You get me? - We get you, sir!
- 星球表面射出电浆 - 虫族炮火
- Plasma, ma'am, from the planet. - Bug batteries.
军事情报说威力应该不强
According to military intelligence, it'll be random and light.
- 部队状况? - 情况是...
- Drop status? - Drop is...
35%降落到地面
35 percent complete, ma'am.
慢慢来 副驾驶
Steady as she goes, Number Two.
记住你的训练 你会活着回去的!
Remember your training, and you will make it back alive!
电浆威力很强 情报有误
This isn't random or light. Someone made a mistake.
部队全都降落了 女士
That's it. We're empty, ma'am.
有人犯了大错
Someone made a big goddam mistake!
快往上飞
Break for high orbit!
走 走 走!
Let's go, let's go, let's go!
强尼!
Johnny!
核弹待命
Rockets up!Rocket crew, move up!
- 核弹小组 利维 瑞哥... - 把它们炸死
- Nuke 'em! Levy! Rico! - Heat 'em up!
- 好了 - 发射
- Set. - Fire!
- 跟我来 - 上吧
- Follow me! - Let's go!
第一排 左翼!
First platoon, left flank!
分散! 第一 二班 跟我来
Split up! First and second squads, follow me.
第二班掩护 第一班跟我
Two, cover! One, with me!
一边到另一边
Along side! Side to side!
开火
Fire!
它们来了
Here they come!
- 王牌 我们该怎么办? - 我...不知道
- Ace, what are we doing? - Uh, I don't know.
- 我不知道 - 把它们全干掉
- I don't know. - Kill them! Kill them all!
上呀
Come on!
找死吗?
Come on! Come on! You want some?
我要你们死!
Here's some! Yeah!
吃子弹吧
Here's some of this!
我的天!
Oh, my God!
苏杰米
Shujimi!
不 不 不!
No, no, no!
救命! 救命! 救命!
Help! Help! Help!
不! 天哪!
No! God!
快走吧
Let's get out of here!
撤退
Fall back!
怎么了?
All units,What's going on? fall back to retrieval.
收到讯号吗?
Repeat.You got com? All units...
全体撤退
fall back to retrieval.It's a general retreat!
- 回运兵船上! - 快!
- Back to the boats! - Come on!
快 我们走!
Come on, let's go!
这里是被称为
We've just landed here on what cap troopers...
大K星的战场
are calling Big K...
第六机动部队展开攻击
with the 6th Mobile Infantry Division.
这丑陋的星球全是大虫
It's an ugly planet, a bug planet.
威胁人类的生存...
A planet hostile to life as we...
救命啊!
Help me!
快向右
Squad right!
快走 快 快 快...
Come on! Go, go, go!
快离开这里
Get out of here now!
- 小心点! - 小心你的侧面! 小心你的侧面!
- Watch your step! - Watch your flank! Watch your flank!
我们被击溃
GXR, we're being overrun.
基顿 不!
Kitten, no!
哦 天哪
Oh, God!
哦 天哪 哦
Oh, God! Oh! Oh!
(联邦电视网)
(一小时内十万人丧命)
人类面临空前危机
Crisis for humankind.
舰队官员承认他们...
Fleet officials admit they underestimated...
低估虫族的防卫能力
the Arachnids' defensive capability.
因为克兰达夫星的惨剧
Accepting responsibility for Klendathu...
狄恩元帅引咎辞职
Sky Marshal Dienes resigns.
新任的元帅马休...
His successor, Sky Marshal Tahat Meru...
宣布她的战略
outlines her new strategy.
我们必须
To fight the bug...
了解虫族才能致胜
we must understand the bug.
我们绝对不能再重蹈克兰达夫的覆辙
We can ill afford another Klendathu.
(你想知道更多吗?)
联邦科学家想...
Federal scientists struggle to explain...
解释虫族的军事智慧
the intelligent military actions of the Arachnids.
虫族经过三百代
When a colony reaches a certain size...
进化一定会变聪明
300 generations or something, it gets smarter.
- 聪明的虫子? - 快...
- Insects with intelligence? - Now, wait...
你遇到过吗? 难以置信...
Have you ever met one? I can't believe...
- 这种想法太荒谬了 - 请你听我说
- I am hearing this nonsense. - Would you just wait a moment?
- 这是我听过的最荒谬讲话 - 可能 可能
- This is the most ridiculous conversation I have ever had. - Maybe... Maybe...
也许有一种虫我们没见过
there is some kind of bug that we haven't seen yet:
领导阶级 虫族首脑
A leadership caste, a-a hive brain.
虫族首脑? 虫子也会思考? 才怪...
Brain Bugs? Frankly, I find the idea of a bug that thinks offensive!
星舰基地 杨罗杰号请求进入
Ticonderoga, this is Rodger Young requesting approach vector.
收到 杨罗杰号
Affirmative, Rodger Young.
座标l00951
One-zero-zero-niner-five-two.
欢迎回来
Welcome back.
我的天
My God.
怎么会这样?
How could this happen?
我们自以为比虫族聪明
We thought we were smarter than the bugs.
(伤亡人数: 308563)
很奇怪 几乎没有人被俘
It's strange. There's almost no wounded at all.
虫族不抓俘虏
Bugs don't take prisoners.
(强尼·瑞哥 阵亡)
哦...不...
Oh, no.
看
Look.
- 卡门... - 这里
- Carmen... - See it? Right there.
- 他在那儿 - 我们会把他叫醒
- There he is. - Come on, we'll just wake him up.
嘿 强尼
Hey,Johnny! Hey!
- 瑞哥 - 强尼 醒醒
- Hey, Rico! - Hey,Johnny!
- 瑞哥 醒醒 - 你好吗 小鱼儿?
- Hey, Rico!Wake up! - How you doin', fish boy?
看 你死了
Hey, look. You're dead!
你阵亡了
Killed in action!
- 再过三天就能出来 - 三天
- Three more days. - Three days.
- 你出局了 - 再见
- And you're out. - Good as new. See you later.
回头见
Bye.
新的部队怎么样?
So what do you hear about our new unit?
硬汉部队消灭的大虫比谁都多
Roughnecks killed more bugs than any other outfit on Big K.
听说中尉很严厉
Yeah, well, I hear their lieutenant's a real nutbuster.
士官长是谁?
Who's top kick?
你想当吗?
You want the job, huh?
我不介意
I wouldn't mind.
我很介意
I would.
我只想出力
Just doing my part.
命令
Orders.
你的呢?
Yours?
你还到哪里打过仗?
Where you been besides Big K?
- 土星外环 西格玛海滩 - 西格玛海滩
- Outer rings, Zegema Beach. - Zegema Beach?
- 我一直想去那儿 - 好运气
- I always wanted to go there. - Good luck.
- 不用去了 那里不存在了 - 听说你们的中尉挺麻烦的
- It's not there any more. - So, I hear your lieutenant's a real nutbuster.
别批评中尉 他救我一命
No one talks about the lieutenant that way.
- 他救过我 - 也救过我
- He saved my life. - Mine too.
- 我也是 - 还有我
- Same for me. - Me too.
听起来他人很好
Well, sounds like he's quite a guy.
你以为是谁救了你?
Who do you think saved your ass?
待命 立正
Stand by. Attention on deck!
新来的听好
This is for you new people.
我只有一个规则
I only have one rule:
全力以赴 不能退缩
Everyone fights. No one quits.
否则我们杀了你们 明白吗?
You don't do your job, I'll shoot you.
明白吗?
Do you get me?
明白 长官
We get you, sir!
- 欢迎到硬汉部队 - 瑞斯加科的硬汉
- Welcome to the Roughnecks. - Rasczak's Roughnecks!
稍息 听好
At ease. Listen up.
新的元帅有新的战略
We got a new Sky Marshal and a new battle plan.
先一一消灭克兰达夫...
We're gonna clean out the systems outlying Klendathu...
周围的星球
one planet at a time.
明天攻击探戈幽灵星
Tomorrow we hit Tango Urilla.
先进行轰炸然后再消灭残留的敌人
After Fleet glasses the planet, MI mops up.
继续吧
Carry on.
好吧 分散开来
All right. Spread out!
核弹小组 找到虫穴就炸掉
Fire teams! You locate a bug hole, nuke it.
华肯 带上弗洛斯和瑞哥
Watkins, shake out Flores and Rico.
收到 走吧
Copy that. Move out!
第一排 我们到山谷
First platoon, we're going for that ridge.
- 利维 跟我来 - 我要跟着瑞哥
- Levy, you're with me. - No, I'm in A Squad. I'm going with Rico.
给我闭嘴
Shut up and follow me!
你喜欢那个?
Hey, you like that?
吃屎的大臭虫
Fungus-sucking sack of maggot puke!
华肯 它死了
It's dead, Watkins! It's dead!
死了就没什么可怕的
Ain't much to look at after you scrape them off your boot.
发现虫穴 那儿
Bug hole. There.
炸掉它 瑞哥
Nuke 'em, Rico!
准备射击
Fire in the hole!
我们受到攻击 快来支援
Watkins, we're under heavy attack. Position M-4.
- 快去! - 快!
- Get over here! - Move!
- 你需要除虫吗 小姐? - 闭嘴 大兵
- You got a bug problem, ma'am? - Ah, stow it, trooper!
大甲虫
Tanker!
- 妈的! - 快走吧
- Oh, shit! - Come on! Move!
趴下来
Get down!
跟我来
Come on!
通知救援队
Stay down, sucker!
呼叫检索
Call for retrieval.
- 医官 - 好身手
- Medic! - Nice moves.
你在哪儿学来的?
Where'd you learn how to do that, soldier?
学校里 你不记得吗?
Back in school, sir. Don't you remember?
- 我是球队队长 - 瑞哥
- I was captain of the team. - Rico?
- 长官 - 我需要一名下士
- Sir. - I need a corporal.
在你阵亡之前你就当下士
You're it until you're dead or till I find somebody better.
谢谢你 长官
Thank you, sir.
- 好了 结束了 - 干得好 下士
- All right, saddle up! Show's over. - Way to go, Corporal.
- 我要一名班长 - 不行 找搞砸过
- Hey, I need a squad leader. - Oh, no. No, I've been there and blew it.
我只想杀敌
I'm just here to fight.
你呢?
What about it, Diz?
看来就是我了
Looks like I'm your girl, sir.
- 待会儿见 - 好
- Catch you later. - All right.
听好
Listen up!
最好的士兵要有最好的享受
I expect the best, and I give the best!
这是啤酒
Here's the beer!
这是娱乐的东西
Here's the entertainment!
玩得开心点 这是命今
Have fun! That's an order!
这是我的
This one's for me!
谢了 中尉
Thank you, Lieutenant!
瑞哥
Rico!
你很会除虫
You kill bugs good.
谢了
Thanks.
你在战前认识中尉了吧
You knew the lieutenant before the war.
他为人如何?
What was he like?
他是个老师 什么都懂
He was a teacher. Kind of like he knew it all.
总是带着微笑
He always had this little smile.
现在他可笑不出来
Yeah, well, he don't smile much any more.
死这么多人怎么笑得出来
Yeah, well, I guess your bottle fills up real quick when your kids get smeared.
- 来吧 下士 - 我不跳舞了
- Come on, Corporal. - Ah, nah, I don't do that any more.
我记得你以前跳 来嘛
I remember when you used to dance. Come on.
我得下令吗?
Do I have to pull rank?
抱歉 长官
Excuse me, sir.
瑞哥 你问过我的意见 想听吗?
Rico. You once asked me for advice. Want some now?
- 想 长官 - 中尉 总部来电
- Yes, sir. - Lieutenant, HQ is on the com.
看到好机会就要把握
Never pass up a good thing.
华肯 喝啤酒吗?
Watkins. Beer?
瑞哥 跳完舞你打算干嘛?
So, Rico, what are you doing after the dance?
有什么好笑?
What's so funny?
世事真是难以预料
You know, just the way things work out.
我们终于在一起
We finally got together, Diz.
我爱你 强尼
I love you,Johnny.
瑞哥
Rico!
准备出动 欧文将军在P星遇难
We're moving out. There's been a distress call from General Owen on Planet P.
穿好军服 十分钟后报到
So get your shit wired and report in ten minutes.
是的
Yes, sir.
谁在那里?
Who's that with you?
弗洛斯 长官
Flores, sir.
二十分钟吧
Make it 20 minutes.
是的 长官
Yes, sir.
二十分钟?
Twenty minutes?
应该来得及
We can do it.
威士忌哨站 收到吗?
Whiskey Outpost, do you copy?
这是硬汉部队201 请回答
This is Roughneck 2-0 on tac three. Come in, please.
威士忌哨站 威士忌哨站
Whiskey Outpost, Whiskey Outpost,
这是硬汉部队201
this is Roughneck 2-0 on tac three.
- 将军有消息吗? - 没有 长官
- Any contact with General Owen? - No, sir.
连发送讯号都没有
Not even the transponder signal.
被山谷挡住 到高处去
It's these canyons. Go to higher ground, Sergeant.
威士忌哨站
Whiskey Outpost, Whiskey Outpost...
这是硬汉部队
this is Roughneck 2-0 on...
把你的枪给我
Sugar, your weapon.
救救我
Help me! Help me!
如果我落入敌手 你们也要杀了我
I'd expect anyone in this unit to do the same for me.
- 瑞哥 - 长官
- Rico. - Sir.
你是代理士官长 带队
You're acting sergeant. Move 'em out.
你们听到了 快走吧
You heard the lieutenant! Saddle up!
天哪 有人血洗这地方
Jeez, someone really humped the bunk.
- 华肯 - 长官
- Watkins. - Sir.
检查哨站 检查死尸
Secure this compound. Police these bodies.
是的 长官 三个人上塔架 快点
Yes, sir. Give me three up on the tower, now!
这里和那里建立监视哨
Aye-aye.OP there! OP there!
检查死尸
Away! Number Two, police up these bodies!
里头好臭
Stinks in there.Second squad, come with me on the gate!
- 瑞哥 - 是的 长官
- Rico! - Yes, sir.
我们需要救援 这地方都是大虫
We need retrieval. This place crawls.
再找人修好通讯连线
Get somebody in the communications tent and get me an uplink.
是的 长官 蒂丝 去吧
Yes, sir. Diz, check it out.
- 知道了 - 指挥小组跟我来
- Roger. - Command group with me.
天哪
Ah, shit.
中尉
Lieutenant!
他们吃饭时遭到大虫偷袭
Dirty bugs came in right while they were having chow.
它们从这里进来
Yeah, this is where they got in.
中尉
Lieutenant.
你最好来看看
I think you're gonna want to see this.
什么事 弗洛斯?
What do you got, Flores?
这地方真可怕
God, I hate this place.
你觉得这是什么? 瑞哥?
What does that look like to you, Rico?
看来虫钻进他大脑
Looks like a bug was in his brain, sir.
它们吸光他大脑
They sucked his brains out.
打开来
Open that.
立正
Officer on the deck!
- 把将军扶起来 - 走了?
- Pick up the general. - Gone?
安全吗? 我们得快走
Is it safe? We've got to get out of here!
- 将军 长官 - 我们...
- General!, Sir! - We've gotta...
谢谢你 谢谢你们
Thank God for you, all of you.
你们都是英雄 你们全都是
You're all gonna be heroes. Every last one of you.
- 把洞穴封起来 - 好的
- Close that hole. - Yes, sir.
我得逃命 联邦秘密太重要
I had to evade capture. The security of the Federation was at stake.
我知道这地区的攻击战略
I have operational knowledge of what we're up to out here.
- 赶快连线 - 我正在努力
- Flores, I need that uplink. - Working on it, sir.
你看
Damn it.See?
它们钻进你的大脑
They get in your mind.Battlegroup, this is Roughneck 2-0.
- 你看法利的下场 - 你知道吗?
- Look, they did it to Farley. - Do you read?
它们钻进你的大脑 逼你做事情
They got in his mind.Come in, Battlegroup. This is Roughneck 2-0.
它们逼法利联络指挥部
They make you do things. They made Farley call headquarters.
求救讯号是个圈套
The distress call was a trap.
它们也想知道我们的底细
They're just like us. They want to know what makes us tick.
摸清我们的弱点 这样才能消灭我们
They want to know us, so they can kill us.
敌人会来袭 准备迎战
Roughnecks, this is lead. Prepare for attack.
- 我们会被攻击 - 救援机在哪呢?
- I repeat, we're gonna be attacked. - Where's the retrieval boat?
紧急状况这是硬汉部队 收到吗?
Mayday. Mayday. This is Roughneck 2-0 to Battlegroup. Do you read?
哦 天哪
Oh, God!
天哪 我们死定了 懂吗?
We're gonna die! Don't you understand?
我们都要死了
We're all gonna die!
第二阵容 跟我来!
Second squad, follow me!
- 克制一下自己 将军 - 不行
- Control yourself, General. - I can't.
我不行 我做不到
I can't.
你干脆杀死我
I wish you'd just shoot me.
中尉 他的脑袋不清楚
Lieutenant! He's just a little out of his mind, sir.
大虫
Bugs! Bugs!
好吧
Die! All right.
准备好 全力开火
Warm it all up! Everything you've got!
- 快 - 大兵们 拚命吧
- Move! - Come on, you apes!
你们想一直活着吧?
You want to live forever?
- 这儿! - 我这边有虫子!
- Here! - I got bugs!
开火吧
Fire at will!
飞虫来袭
Incoming!
瑞哥 连线好了吗?
Rico, where's my communication?
- 蒂丝 连线呢? - 再等一分钟
- Diz, status on the uplink! - Give me a minute.
我们没有一分钟了
We don't have a minute!
舰队 这是硬汉部队
Battlegroup, this is Roughneck 2-0. We are under...
- 这里是杨罗杰号 请说 - 我们受袭 请来救援
- This is Rodger Young. Go ahead. - We are under attack, sir. We need retrieval now!
P星球没敌人
We have Planet Pas clear.
到处都是 快来接人
This place crawls, sir. We need pickup now!
- 说出位置 - 追踪无线电讯号
- What's your position? - Come down on this transmission.
哨站? 太疯狂了
Inside the outpost? That's crazy!
希望飞行员也疯狂 完毕
Well, I hope you have a crazy pilot. Out!
中尉
Lieutenant!
救援机正赶来
Boat coming down, sir!
退进去 快撤
Fall back into the compound! Fall back!
全力抵挡敌人
Hold here! Hold what you've got!
弹药快没了
Running low!
我没了
I'm out!
拿去 省着点
Here! Make 'em count!
掩护救援机 撤
Make cover fire! Fall back!
快 快 快
Move, move, move!
快登机 撤
Fall back to the boat! Haul ass!
- 我的天 - 哦
- Oh, my God! - Oh!
- 把他拉上来 - 快
- Get him outta there! Pull! - Come on!
瑞哥 瑞哥
Rico! Rico!
- 你知道该怎么做 - 是的 长官
- You know what to do! - Yes, sir!
快下手 瑞哥
Do it, Rico!
- 嗯! - 蒂丝!
- Yeah! - Dizzy!
不!
No!
王牌 帮我拉住她
Ace, help me! Hold her down!
把她抬上机
Move! Get her into the boat!
蒂丝 千万别死
Come on, Diz! Don't die on me!
把她抬走 快
Let's get her out! Let's go, let's go!
快上去
Let's go! Get aboard!
你们 快点...
Tower, let's go!
快来吧
Let's move it, tower! Run!
升空
Lift off!
- 强尼 我快死了 - 不
- Johnny, I'm dying-dying. - No.
不 你不会有事的 蒂丝
You're gonna be all right, Diz.
没关系
It's all right...
因为我爱过你
because I got to have you.
别放开我
Johnny, don't let me go!
强...强...
Joh...Joh...
别放开...别放开...
Don't let... Don't let...
我要你知道
I think you should know...
你的朋友瑞哥在后面
your friend Rico is back there.
快通知舰队轰炸这星球
Get on the com and tell Fleet to glass that rock.
谁下的命令 下士?
On whose authority, Corporal?
我的命令 任务由我指挥
That would be mine, sir. I assumed command of the mission.
杨罗杰号 我正式代表
Rodger Young, we have an official request...
机动部队要求轰炸P星球
by the Mobile Infantry to commence bombardment of Planet P.
我以为你死了
I thought you were dead.
我没死 很多战友都死了
I'm not, but a lot of my troopers are.
不行
Negative on your request, DeRuyter.
元帅另有安排
The Sky Marshal has other plans for Planet P.
欢迎回来
Welcome back.
机动部队负责死 舰队负责飞
MI does the dying. Fleet just does the flying.
等等 有动静了
Hold on. Something's up.
舰队要进行大规模行动
Fleet's mobilized for a big operation.
立正
Attention on deck!
有人曾问我...
Once somebody asked me...
公民和平民...
if I knew the difference between a citizen...
有何不同
and a civilian.
我现在知道了
I can tell you now.
公民有...
A citizen has the courage...
捍卫人类安全的勇气
to make the safety of the human race their personal responsibility.
蒂丝是我朋友
Dizzy was my friend.
她也是战士
She was a soldier.
更重要的是
But more than that...
她是联邦公民
she was a citizen of the Federation.
敬礼
Present arms!
放下
Order arms!
向左转
Left face!
- 立正 - 继续
- Officer on deck! - Carry on.
治葬队伍解散
Burial detail dismissed.
稍息
At ease.
- 你好吗 卡尔? - 我很好 卡门
- How are you, Carl? - Carmen, good.
强尼 我很遗憾你们被派到P星球
Johnny, I'm sorry it had to be your unit on P.
那次任务的生还率很低
That mission had a very low survival probability.
虫族设下圈套 对吧?
The bugs laid a trap for us, didn't they?
证明它们有智慧
Elegant proof of intelligence, isn't it?
我早就猜到P星球上有虫族首脑
We thought there might be a Brain Bug on P.
你早就知道却派他们下去?
You knew, and you sent them anyway?
我们找不到首脑就不能进行攻击
We couldn't afford to launch an operation if there wasn't one.
你不苟同 很遗憾
You don't approve. Well, too bad.
事关人类存亡
We're in this for the species, boys and girls.
它们数量众多
It's simple numbers. They have more.
我每天都得决定...
And every day I have to make decisions...
派你这种人去送死
that send hundreds of people like you to their deaths.
难道你不知道吗 中校?
Didn't they tell you, Colonel?
机动部队专门送死
That's what the Mobile Infantry is good for.
希望你还能再战
I hope you're ready for more.
我们要回去活抓首脑
We're going back to P to capture that Brain.
硬汉部队随时备战
The Roughnecks are always ready, sir.
他们需要一名中尉 想当吗?
I hear they need a new lieutenant. Want the job?
好的 等我阵亡你再换人
I'll take it, till I get killed or you find someone better.
全体人员报到
Attention. All personnel report to your stations.
- 好吧 - 75分钟后降落
- Well... - Prepare for drop in 75 minutes.
你要小心 强尼
Take care of yourself,Johnny.
后会有期
I'll see you again.
立正
Officer on deck!
- 这些孩子是谁? - 支援部队
- Who are all these kids? - We got reinforced.
多半是菜鸟
Most of them are fresh out of boot.
我们算是老兵
We're the old men, Ace.
新兵听好
This is for all you new people.
我只有一个规则
I only have one rule:
全力以赴 不能退缩
Everyone fights. No one quits.
不尽力我就亲自宰了你
If you don't do your job, I'll kill you myself.
明白吗?
Do you get me?
明白 长官
We get you, sir!
- 欢迎加入硬汉部队 - 瑞哥的硬汉部队
- Welcome to the Roughnecks. - Rico's Roughnecks!
今天要进入虫穴
Today we're gonna pay a visit to Bug City.
找一只没见过的大虫
We're lookin' for a bug no one's ever seen before.
一只聪明的虫子
Some kind of smart bug.
它可能知道我们要去 来吧
And it probably knows we're comin'.
快! 跑 跑 跑
Come on! Run, run, run, run, run!
快闪躲
Evasive action.
准备进行超光速飞行
Get us clear for warp, Number Two.
五秒后 四...三...
Clear in five, four...
- 开始转换超光速引擎... - 三...五
- Initiating star drive... - three...in five.
杨罗杰号被击中 就快坠毁
This is Rodger Young. We're going down Repeat, this is Rodger Young.
- 快离开这里 - 弃舰...
- Get out! We're going down. - Abandon ship! Come on!
卡门!
Carmen! Oh!
- 山德! - 这!
- Zander! - Here!
- 快赶去逃生艇 - 来吧
- We've got to get to the rescue deck! - Come on!
舰长
Captain!
快弃舰 这是命...
Abandon ship. That's an...
她死了 卡门 她死了
She's dead, Carmen. She's dead!
这儿
Go! Here!
跟我来
Follow me!
好了吗?
Ready?
B63逃生艇 两人在艇上
Life pod Bravo 6-3, two aboard.
搜寻降落点 扫瞄地形 这儿
Scanning for a landing zone! Checking terrain. Here!
- 你行吗? - 小意思
- Can you handle that? - Piece of cake.
- 我们失去了杨罗杰号 - 你们在什么位置?
- We've lost the Rodger Young! - What is your position?
经过确实 杨罗杰号坠毁
Flight Command, we have confirmation. The Rodger Young is down.
强尼
Oh.Johnny!
Johnny!
杨罗杰号遭击毁
Rodger Young just burned up.
在救援
It's on the rescue net.
有没有生还者?
Any survivors?
情况很糟
Well, they're getting tarred up there pretty bad.
B63逃生艇
Bravo 6-3, two aboard.
收到吗?
Is anyone receiving?
- 有人收到吗? - 收到
- Is anyone receiving? - Affirmative.
这里是硬汉部队
This is Roughneck 2-0.
讯号中断 请重覆
You're breaking up. Say again.
- 卡门? - 请重复 信号中断
- Carmen? - Say again. I'm losing you.
卡门!
Carmen!
准备降落
Prepare for landing.
反向推动器 三...
Retros in three...
二...一...启动
two, one, fire!
卡门 卡门
Carmen. Carmen.
- 你没事吧? - 嗯
- Hey, are you okay? - Uh-huh.
快下来
Get out. Get out.
这是硬汉部队 收到吗?
This is Roughneck 2-0. Are you receiving? Over. This is Roughneck 2-0.
- 卡门 你收到吗? - 强尼 是你吗?
- Carmen, are you receiving? - Johnny, is that you?
是我 你的位置和状况如何?
It's me! Wh, what's your position and situation?
我们在虫穴 地下二十米
We're in Bug City, 20 metres underground.
位置是...南42 东118
Position: south 42, east 118.
状况...
Situation is...
重复 南42 东118
I repeat. South 42, east 118.
状况呢?
What's your situation? Over.
卡门
Carmen.
状况很危险
Situation is extremely hostile.
快派小队救援
I need a squad to pull 'em out!
- 方向? - 西南方三公里
- Direction? - Three clicks, south by southwest.
小心
Look out!
- 怎么办? - 大伙听到了
- What do you wanna do? - You heard the lieutenant.
救援队 第三班跟我来
Rescue party! Third squad, come with me!
取消命令
Cancel that!
我们都知道她已经死了
You know as well as I do, she's already dead.
很遗憾 老兄
Sorry, buddy.
硬汉部队 前进
Roughnecks, let's move.
好
All right.
它们为何不杀死我们?
Why didn't they kill us?
它们要活捉我们
They want us alive.
我们应该走这边
We should go this way.
A连前往这方向
A Company's that way.
没错 可是卡门在这儿
Yeah, but Carmen's down there.
恕我直言 老兄 她已经死了
Hey, I hate to be rude, buddy, but word has it she's dead.
她还活着
She's still alive.
你怎么知道?
How do you know?
- 别问我 我就是知道 - 听着
- I don't know how I know, but I know. - Listen.
指挥官违反命令的...
You got command, but going off mission...
罪名很重
That's a serious offence.
你会被判吊刑
I think they hang you for that.
硬汉20部队继续前进
Roughneck 2-0, proceed on mission.
我要两名自愿者
I need two volunteers.
有一天
One day...
像我这样的人...
someone like me...
会消灭你们...
is gonna kill you...
整个臭虫族
and your whole fucking race.
你知道这是什么吗?
You know what this is?
你当然知道
Sure you do.
你是肥大的聪明虫
You're some kind of big, fat, smart bug...
对吧?
aren't you?
来吧
Come on.
这是硬汉部队
This is Roughneck 2-0.
虫族首脑往西五区前进
Brain Bug sighted moving west of grid five.
快跑
Run!
快 快
Go! Go!
- 核弹给我 - 你想当英雄吗?
- Give me the nuke! - You trying to be a hero, Watkins?
我想要除虫
I'm trying to kill some bugs, sir!
你们快走
Get outta here! Get outta here!
快走吧
Move!
来啊 想死吗
Come on! You like that? You like that? Come on!
想死吗? 吃子弹吧
You want a little more?
You like that? You like that? You like that? You like that? You want a little more?
来呀 来呀
Come on! Come on!
走吧
Come on, come on, come on!
来吧 卡门
Come on, Carmen.
我们成功了!
We did it! We won!
- 怎么回事? - 逮到它了
- What's going on? - They got it!
来呀
Come on!
它在想什么 中校?
What's it thinking, Colonel?
它很害怕
It's afraid.
怕得要命
It's afraid!
- 快 - 好!
- Come on. - Yeah!
卡尔! 卡尔!
Carl! Carl! Hey!
你们还活着 很好
Well, look who's here. You made it. Good.
你教我的 是你教我去找卡门
It was you, wasn't it? You told me how to find Carmen.
这是机密
Well, that's classified.
我们三个在一起就...
You know, whenever the three of us are together...
能无往不胜
I feel like things might just work out.
希望你说的对 卡门
I hope you're right, Carmen.
我们逮到虫族首脑 很快就知道它们的弱点
We've got one of their Brains now. Pretty soon we'll know how they think.
这样一来就能击败它们
And then we'll know how to beat them.
有一天战争会结束
One day it will all be over...
大家会忘记这场奋战的功臣
and everyone will forget that this was the moment.
回想之时
This is when it turned.
不是强大的舰队或是犀利的武器
And it wasn't the mighty Fleet, it wasn't some fancy new weapon.
而是逮到虫族首脑的辛姆教官
It was a drill instructor named Zim who captured a Brain.
- 好 - 辛姆?
- Yeah! - Zim?
辛姆逮到大虫
Zim. Zim got the bug.
Zim got the bug, man!
- 干得好 中士 - 谢谢你 长官
- Good job, Sergeant. - Thank you, sir.
- 我是二等兵 - 继续 二等兵
- That would be private, sir. - Carry on, Private.
- 是的 长官 - 好
- Yes, sir! - Yeah!
虫族首脑将透露什么秘密?
What mysteries will the Brain Bug reveal?
科学家日以继夜 探索它的奥秘
Federal scientists are working around the clock to probe its secrets.
一旦了解虫族就能消灭它们
Once we understand the bug, we will defeat it.
我们有舰队
We have the ships.
我们有武器
We have the weapons.
我们需要战士
We need soldiers.
像丝黛克中尉这种战士
Soldiers like Lieutenant Stack Lumbrezer.
抵达目标区 舰长
We're over the target area now, Captain.
- 还有卡门·艾邦妮兹舰长 - 我是舰长
- And Captain Carmen Ibanez. - This is the captain speaking.
准备降落
All personnel prepare for drop.
二等兵利维和瑞哥中尉
Soldiers like Private Ace Levy and Lieutenant John Rico.
大兵们 拚命吧
Come on, you apes! You wanna live forever?
我们需要你
We need you all.
服役就有公民权
Service guarantees citizenship.
(继续奋战)
(胜利在望)